<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Haitian Things to Do Before You Die</title>
    <link>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Haitian Things to Do Before You Die</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:30:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Read The Black Jacobins</title>
      <link>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/jacobins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:30:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/jacobins/</guid>
      <description>The Black Jacobins is a historical account of the Haitian Revolution, written by C.L.R. James. The book describes the revolution as a culmination of decades of resistance by enslaved Africans and Afro-Caribbeans against the French colonial regime in Saint-Domingue, now Haiti. James argues that the revolution was not only a slave rebellion, but also a social revolution that transformed the colony and the world. He also highlights the role of Toussaint L&amp;rsquo;Ouverture, a former slave who emerged as the leader of the rebellion and the father of Haiti&amp;rsquo;s independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soup Joumou</title>
      <link>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/soup-joumou/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:30:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/soup-joumou/</guid>
      <description>Soup Joumou, also known as pumpkin soup, is a traditional Haitian dish that holds a significant cultural and historical significance. The dish is particularly associated with the Haitian Revolution, which began in 1791 and ended in 1804 with the establishment of Haiti as the world&amp;rsquo;s first black republic. According to legend, the soup was once a delicacy reserved for the French colonizers and was prohibited for enslaved Haitians to consume. However, on January 1st, 1804, Haiti declared its independence, and the first thing the enslaved Haitians did was to cook and enjoy a bowl of soup joumou as a symbol of their newfound freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit the Citadel</title>
      <link>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:30:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fzgrandchamps.github.io/haiti-103/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The Citadel, also known as the Citadelle Laferrière, is a majestic fortress located in the northern region of Haiti. Built in the early 19th century by Henri Christophe, a former slave and leader of the Haitian Revolution, this fortress stands as a testament to the determination and resilience of the Haitian people. Rising high above the surrounding landscape, the Citadel is not only a formidable fortress but also an architectural masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>